Finding aid to Association of Former Juniors in France Records CA.MS.00327
Smith College Archives
Association of Former Juniors in France Records
1925-1973
Smith College Archives
Association of Former Juniors in France
CA.MS.00327
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
Contains correspondence, photographs, financial records, publications, minutes, and news clippings.
Biographical / Historical
In 1927, the first Smith College juniors studied abroad in Paris, France. Nine years later, in 1936, the Association of Former Juniors in France was established by college alumnae who had participated in the Paris Junior Year Abroad program. The primary goal of the association was to fund a scholarship for future Smith students to study abroad in France. The secondary aim of the members was to stay up-to-date on information regarding both France and the Smith students currently studying abroad in the country. In addition, the association raised money to aid French soldiers and refugees displaced due to World War II, including sponsoring French children and their families. Holding an annual dinner in New York City, the members actively fundraised while reconnecting with old friends and maintaining a strong alumnae network. The association also published a newsletter, Trait D'Union, which included articles from both former and current Smith students, commentary from various professors, and updates on French politics, music, cinema, and books. While having a lively membership for over thirty years, the Association of Former Juniors in France was no longer active by the mid-1970s.
Scope and Contents
The Association of Former Juniors in France records consist of files relating to club activity from 1936 to 1972. Types of materials include: correspondence, information pertaining to the founding of the French House, invitations, photographs, meeting minutes and notices, records of World War II relief efforts, membership lists, organization and officer information, scholarship records, and publications.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Association of Former Juniors in France records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
- Anniversaries, 1950 (Box 1133, Folder 1)
- Articles and pamphlets, 1955-1966 (Box 1133, Folder 2)
- Correspondence: general, 1931-1950 (Box 1133, Folder 3)
- Correspondence: Alumnae Association, 1943-1945 (Box 1133, Folder 4)
- Correspondence: (Box 1133)
- Alder, Emily Frank, 1942 (Box 1133, Folder 5)
- Alward, Jane, 1955 (Box 1133, Folder 6)
- Benjamin, Alice Louise, 1950 (Box 1133, Folder 7)
- Boname, Mary, 1938-1960 (Box 1133, Folder 8)
- Bourgoin, Louise M., 1942-1943 (Box 1133, Folder 9)
- Brooks, Nathalie Jeanne, 1938-1942 (Box 1133, Folder 10)
- Burrell, Jane, 1938-1949 (Box 1133, Folder 11)
- Cattanes, Helene, 1942-1960 (Box 1133, Folder 12)
- Davis, Herbert, 1943 (Box 1133, Folder 13)
- Delpit, Louise, 1938-1948 (Box 1133, Folder 14)
- Emerson, Harriet, 1939 (Box 1133, Folder 15)
- Freschl, Lisbeth Newelt, 1947 (Box 1133, Folder 16)
- Freyss, Beatrice, 1938 (Box 1133, Folder 17)
- Goube, Pierre, 1944-1946 (Box 1133, Folder 18)
- Guilloton, Vincent, 1943-1944; undated (Box 1133, Folder 19)
- Healy, Marjorie, 1938 (Box 1133, Folder 20)
- Imbault-Huart, Yvonne, 1938-1949; undated (Box 1133, Folder 21)
- Lagarde, Charlotte, 1949 (Box 1133, Folder 22)
- Messieres, Rene de, 1949-1950 (Box 1133, Folder 23)
- Neilson, William Allan, 1938-1944 (Box 1133, Folder 24)
- O'Brien, Mary, 1934 (Box 1133, Folder 25)
- Powers, Helen, 1943 (Box 1133, Folder 26)
- Rosenfield, Leonora, 1962; undated (Box 1133, Folder 27)
- Railo, Carol, 1963 (Box 1133, Folder 28)
- Saliel, Jeanne, 1950-1965 (Box 1133, Folder 29)
- Stapleton, Florence, 1929-1968 (Box 1133, Folder 30)
- French House, 1941-1949 (Box 1133, Folder 31)
- French war relief, 1940-1948 (Box 1133, Folder 32)
- French War Relief Unit: New York, 1944-1945 (Box 1133, Folder 33)
- History, 1965; undated (Box 1133, Folder 34)
- Invitations, 1963-1969; undated (Box 1133, Folder 35)
- Meetings, 1936-1938 (Box 1133, Folder 36)
- Meetings, 1939 (Box 1133, Folder 37)
- Meetings, 1940 (Box 1133, Folder 38)
- Meetings, 1941 (Box 1133, Folder 39)
- Meetings, 1942 (Box 1133, Folder 40)
- Meetings, 1943 (Box 1133, Folder 41)
- Meetings, 1944-1949 (Box 1133, Folder 42)
- Meetings, 1950-1954 (Box 1133, Folder 43)
- Meetings, 1955-1967 (Box 1133, Folder 44)
- Membership lists, 1925-1941 (Box 1134, Folder 1)
- Officers, 1942-1945 (Box 1134, Folder 2)
- Organization, general information, 1939-1972; undated (Box 1134, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1944; undated (Box 1134, Folder 4)
- Publications: Trait D'Union, 1939-1949 (Box 1134, Folder 5)
- Publications: Trait D'Union, 1950-1973 (Box 1134, Folder 6)
- Publications: Trait D'Union archives (bound copies), 1938-1965 (Box 1134, Folder 7)
- Publications: Trait D'Union book list, 1939-1944 (Box 1134, Folder 8)
- Publications: Trait D'Union correspondence, 1938-1950. (Box 1134, Folder 9)
- Scholarships, 1939-1959 (Box 1134, Folder 10)
- Scholarships: Campbell, Edith Sumner, 1953-1964 (Box 1134, Folder 11)
- Treasurers' reports, 1939-1955 (Box 1134, Folder 12)